Veniamin **Tsigourof**

{Front End Web Developer}

Contact Details

https://bentsigourof.cool



https://www.linkedin.com/in/veniamin-tsigourof/





tsigourof.ben@gmail.com



S ben.tsigourof

PROFILE

Hi! My name is Veniamin Tsigourof (feel free to call me Ben) and I am a front end developer, currently transitioning from a career in geomatics engineering to software-engineering. I'm passionate about JavaScript & love working with React is, I like coding things from scratch and shape ideas into apps that offer great user experiences across all devices & browsers and are accessible to all users. Coding is my passion and it drives me to constantly improve and learn new things.

SKILLS

- Key Skills: JavaScript (ES6+), React.js, HTML5, CSS3.
- Responsive Design: CSS Grid Layout, Flexbox, Material-UI, Bootstrap 3 & 4.
- Version Control: Git/GitHub.
- Libraries/Tools: Jasmine, ¡Query, Gulp
- Accessibility: ARIA, A11Y.
- Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, MongoDB, mongoose.js.
- Software: Photoshop, ArcGIS, qGIS, AutoCAD, Verm5.

PROJECTS

My Portfolio: A mobile & screen-reader friendly single page application build with React.js. Sempernote: A full stack note taking app with a "what you see is what you get" text editor. Build with React.js, Material-UI, Quill.js for the front-end and Node, Express, MongoDB and GraphQL for the back-end. Flickr photo Plotter: A single page application build with React is and the Google Maps API, that uses the geolocation metadata from Flickr API to plot photographs on the map based on the location that the photo was taken.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Municipality of Komotini - Directorate of Technical Services

Komotini - Greece Apr 2017 - Dec 2017

Surveying Engineer

- Coordinated and led a team of four engineers to perform preliminary and as-built surveys of public spaces including public squares, parks, roads, playgrounds and Historical Buildings.
- Produced maps of the surveyed areas.
- Updated and maintained municipality's internal GIS System.

Topographic Service of the Hellenic Ministry of Rural Development

Komotini - Greece Dec 2015 - May 2016

GIS analyst

- Set up a publicly accessible GIS system depicting property boundaries and ownership data of the land issued by H.M.R.D.
- Merged and analyzed more than $950km^2$ of spatial data referring to property boundaries and ownership data issued by H.M.R.D.
- Identified more than 160 land parcels that had inconsistencies with National Cadastre.

EDUCATION

- Front-End Web Developer *NanoDegree* (part of the Grow with Google Scholarship). Udacity, Feb 2018 - Aug 2018.
- Google Developer Challenge Scholarship. Udacity, Nov 2017 Feb 2018.
- BSc in Geoinformatics and Surveying Engineering. Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia. Greece 2003-2009